November 25, 2016

**OCZ Storage Solutions** 6373 San Ignacio Ave San Jose, CA 95119 USA

Re: Social Media Intern

Dear Hiring Manager:

My name is Brandon Lin, currently a student at the University of Pennsylvania. I plan to major in Computer Science and Chemical Engineering. I became aware of the Social Media Internship at OCZ via recommendations from my writing seminar class. Upon reviewing the position, I believe that this internship is perfect for me based on my experiences and skills.

Writing has always been an enjoyable activity for me, and to apply it to managing social media would be an invaluable experience for me in any career path. I currently run a YouTube channel, where I learned the true value of social media in today's modern age. In my YouTube channel, I post videos of Rubik's Cube solves, footage at national competitions, as well as tutorials teaching others how to solve puzzles and how to get faster. Currently, the channel has over 2000 subscribers, along with nearly 300 likes on its associated Facebook page. The skills that I have obtained via running a YouTube channel regarding being known on social media are directly applicable to the internship; for example, by analyzing social data for OCZ's target audiences and making posts and media content directly catering to them.

Additionally, being the chief editor of my high school's math journal not only taught me the skills required to oversee the editing of a school journal, but also some indispensible writing techniques. As evident in my writing portfolio, I am aware about how to write effective works of prose, such as a literature review investigating the evolution of the field of chromosomal analysis, as well as a public argument piece advocating research for newer fields of genetic medicine. Using very detailed logical reasoning allows me to write coherent papers, and there is no doubt that my skills would be greatly useful in this internship when it comes to writing for web pages or social media.

I would be willing to be interviewed for this Social Media Internship so I can speak about my experiences more. Please do not hesitate to contact me at branlin@sas.upenn.edu if you have further questions. Thank you for your time.

Sincerely,

Brandon Lin

Brandon List

# Brandon Lin

# University of Pennsylvania

#### Programming

- Python
- Java
- LaTeX
- HTML/CSS
- o C

## **Applications**

- Microsoft Word/Excel/PPT
- Github
- Java Processing
- Python Flask
- o Jinja2
- GIMP

## **Operating Systems**

- Windows
- Ubuntu Linux

#### Social Media

- Facebook
- Snapchat
- YouTube

## Other Interests

- Rubik's Cube
- Music
- Videography

## Education

2016–present University of Pennsylvania, College of Arts and Sciences, Philadelphia, PA.

**Candidate for Bachelor of Arts** in May 2020

2012–2016 **Stuyvesant High School**, New York, NY.

Graduated with Advanced NYS Regents Diploma – Cumulative GPA: 4.00

## Work Experience

2016–present Penn Labs, Developer.

 Back-end developer working with the Penn Undergraduate Assembly to build software for the Penn student body

2016–present **Art of Problem Solving**, *Grader/Teaching Assistant*.

Assisting instructors by grading student solutions to various olympiad math classes

# Leadership & Volunteer Experience

2016–present **Penn Cubing**, *President*.

Rubik's Cube speedcubing club at the University of Pennsylvania

2015–2016 Stuyvesant HS Computer Science Dojo, Leader/Sensei.

• Tutored students of Introduction to Computer Science and AP Computer Science in daily after-school sessions, helping with homework and test preparation

2014–2016 Stuyvesant HS Speed Cubed, President.

• Ran Stuyvesant HS's Rubik's Cube club to build speedcubing community

Organized citywide competition for speedcubers to promote speedcubing in NYC

2013–2014 North Shore LIJ/Northwell Health, Volunteer.

• Prepared posters for weekly meetings and created lab checklists

• Assisted with escort and transport of patients to their proper locations

# Other Experiences

2015–2016 Stuyvesant HS Math Survey, Editor In-Chief.

• Wrote and compiled articles for Stuyvesant HS's math journal

2011-present World Cube Association, Competitor.

 Volunteering and competing in various worldwide Rubik's Cube competitions in the Northeast region

# **Programming Projects**

2014 VirtCube, Java Processing.

o Created a virtual Rubik's Cube built in Java Processing

## Awards and Achievements

- Guinness World Record Holder for Square-1 Average (Rubik's Cube)
- USA Computing Olympiad Gold Division Qualifier
- American Invitational Math Examination (AIME) Qualifier (2013-2016)